=======================================================================================================================================

Numotion Privacy Policy
=======================

### **Numotion Website Privacy Policy**

Last Updated: December 27, 2022  
  
Welcome to our Privacy Policy. It applies to this and all other Numotion websites and apps, including MyNumotion (collectively, the “Site”).  To the extent any customer information collected is Protected Health Information (“PHI”) under HIPAA, it is governed by our [Numotion Notice of Privacy Practices](https://www.numotion.com/privacy).  

**Information we collect**  
We may collect the following types of information:

* Information you provide – When you sign up for access to our online resources (including any customer applications), download documents or complete online forms, we may ask you for certain personal information. You may be asked to provide personal information such as: name, title, function, e-mail address, address and certain demographic information. When placing an order or carrying out a transaction on the Site, you may be asked for financial information such as credit card details. You may also voluntarily share other information such as feedback, opinions, or information shared via the Contact Us feature.
* Cookies – A cookie is a piece of data stored on a user’s computer that is tied to information about the user. When you visit the Site, we send one or more cookies to your computer or other browsing device. We use cookies to improve the quality of our service, including for storing user preferences, improving search results and ad selection, and tracking user trends. We use Google Analytics to help us understand how visitors are interacting with the Site.  Information about Google Analytics and its use of cookies can be found at [www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/). Most browsers are initially set up to accept cookies, but you can reset your browser to refuse cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, some Site features and services may not function properly if your cookies are disabled. 
* Web beacons – Web pages may contain electronic images (called a “single-pixel GIF” or “web beacon”) that allow a web site to count users who have visited that page or to access certain cookies. We use web beacons to track the effectiveness of an email campaign and to transfer an individual’s unique user identification (often in the form of a cookie) and associate your updated information into our database. Our practice is to include web beacons in HTML-formatted email messages (messages that include graphics) that we send directly or through third parties in order to determine, among many other items, which email messages were opened and to note whether a message was acted upon. In general, any electronic image viewed as part of a web page, including an ad banner, can act as a web beacon.
* Log information – When you access the Site via a browser, application or other client, our servers automatically record certain information. This may include information such as your web request, your interaction with a service, Internet Protocol (IP) address, browser type, browser language, the date and time of your request, and one or more cookies that may uniquely identify your browser or your account.
* Customer due diligence information – When you request services from us, we may obtain information from public record sources, credit reporting agencies or other customer due diligence providers. 

**Children under the age of 16**  

Our Site is not intended for children under 16 years of age. If we learn we have collected or received personal information from a child under 16 without verification of parental consent, we will delete that information. If you believe we might have any information from or about a child under 16, please contact us at privacy.security@numotion.com or (833) 998-2027.  

**How we use this information**

* We use information we collect to help us improve the Site and deliver content and functionality that is best suited for you and your device.
* To analyze your use of the Site for trend monitoring and promotional purposes
* The information we collect allows us to keep you posted on our latest announcements, events, and services that we believe may be of interest to you if this is in accordance with your marketing preferences.
* We may use your information to send important notices or communications regarding services you have ordered from us, even if you have opted out from our marketing communications.
* To respond to inquiries and comments and provide you with support via your preferred communication channels
* To keep the Site safe and secure and comply with our legal requirements and obligations
* To set up and manage your user account
* For any other new purpose for which we notify you before collecting any personal data

**How we share your information**  

You can choose which, if any, of our online resources you wish to participate in. We only share personal information in the following limited circumstances:

* We provide information to our subsidiaries and affiliated companies where it is necessary to meet the purpose for which you have submitted your personal data such as the provision of services, account administration, sales, marketing and support.  
* To third party contractors and providers that perform certain functions on our behalf, such as sending email, removing repetitive information from customer lists, analyzing data and processing credit card payments, direct marketing services, cloud hosting services, and customer due diligence and credit checks. These parties only have access to such information as necessary to perform their functions and may not use it for any purpose other than to provide services to us.
* We may also share personal data directly relevant to investigating and handling a criminal or civil lawsuit, regulatory investigation or to take action to prevent fraud, abuse or other violations of our Site Terms of Use.
* For other lawful purposes that may arise such as due to any merger, acquisition, financing, sale of company assets or interests in the company, or transition of service to another provider, or in the event of an insolvency, bankruptcy, or receivership.

**Safeguarding your information**  

We use commercially reasonable efforts to employ security measures designed to protect your personal information from loss, destruction, or access by unauthorized persons. These include, but are not limited to:

* Physical safeguards such as locked doors and file cabinets, controlled access to our facilities and secure destruction of media containing your personal information.
* Technology safeguards, like the use of anti-virus and endpoint protection software, and monitoring of our systems and data centers to ensure that they comply with our security policies.
* Organizational safeguards, like training and awareness programs on security and privacy, to make sure employees understand the importance and means by which they must protect your personal information.

**Data Retention**  

We will retain your information for as long as is necessary for the purposes for which it was collected. The criteria used to determine our retention periods include:

* How long is the data needed to provide you with our products or services or to operate our business?
* Do you have an account with us? In this case, we will keep your data while your account is active or for as long as needed to provide the services to you.
* Are we subject to a legal, contractual, or similar obligation to retain your data? Examples can include mandatory data retention laws in the applicable jurisdiction, government orders to preserve data relevant to an investigation, or data that must be retained for the purposes of contract or litigation.

**Accessing and controlling your information**  

You have the following rights in most circumstances:

* The right of access—The right to know whether data concerning you is being processed and if so, the right to gain access to it with a few exceptions.
* The right to rectification—The right to ensure data held about you is accurate, and if it is not, have it corrected.
* The right to erasure or right to be forgotten—Where we do not have an overriding legal basis to retain your personal information.
* The right to restrict processing—In some circumstances, you have the right to limit how we process your personal information if we do not have an overriding legal basis to continue processing.
* The right to be informed—we have a responsibility to provide you with the information contained in this privacy policy and to answer questions if you ask for more detail about anything contained here.
* The right to data portability—The right to obtain a copy of the personal data you provided to us, in a format you can easily take away and load onto another device.
* The right to object—You have the right to withdraw consent or object to processing when processing is based upon consent or legitimate interest as the lawful basis, with some exceptions.

For many of our services, we provide mechanisms for you to electronically access and update your personal information by logging into your online accounts. You may opt-out of promotional email communications from us by clicking on a link provided in our promotional email messages or sending us an email at [accounts@numotion.com](mailto:accounts@numotion.com). After opting-out, you will no longer receive marketing or promotional communications but will continue to receive other messages, such as important notices or communications regarding services you have ordered from us. You may also send any access requests to [privacy.security@numotion.com](mailto:privacy.security@numotion.com) or complete our online [personal information request form](https://www.numotion.com/personal-information-request-form).  Please provide details of your specific request.  

**California residents: Your California privacy rights**

California law permits residents or their agents to receive: (1) a listing of categories of personal information we have collected about them, (2) the identity of any third parties to whom we have disclosed personal information for a business purpose or sold personal information within the previous calendar year and (3) the categories of personal information disclosed or sold to those third parties. California law requires us to request certain personal information to verify your identity prior to these disclosures and prohibits discrimination based on your exercise of these rights.  You can submit a request for disclosure by contacting us at [californiaprivacy@numotion.com](mailto:californiaprivacy@numotion.com), calling toll-free (833) 998-2027 or completing our online [personal information request form](https://www.numotion.com/personal-information-request-form).   
  
We may provide referral information to our subsidiaries and affiliates where that Numotion-owned company can better serve a customer’s needs, such as referring self-pay clients to SpinLife.  If you would like to opt-out of such referrals, please email us at [accounts@numotion.com](mailto:accounts@numotion.com), call us toll-free at (833) 998-2027 or complete our online [personal information request form](https://www.numotion.com/personal-information-request-form). Please note that we do **not** sell or share your personal information with organizations outside the Numotion group for their marketing purposes.  Nor do we use or disclose sensitive personal information for purposes other than those specified in Section 7027(m) of the California Consumer Privacy Act (CCPA).   

**Questions or concerns**  
  
If you would like more information about any of the above, have concerns, or need information about viewing this Privacy Policy in alternate formats, you can contact the Privacy Officer at [privacy.security@numotion.com](mailto:privacy.security@numotion.com) or toll-free

Sign up for What's Nu Impacting You
-----------------------------------

Receive the most current news and important information you need.

Call our National Customer Care Center at [800-500-9150](tel:+18005009150).

**Numotion is the nation’s leading provider of Complex Rehab Technology (CRT) with an array of mobility solutions and medical supplies for adults and pediatrics.**

ATTENTION: If you speak another language, language assistance services, free of charge, are available to you. Call 1-800-368-1019, or TTY: 800-537-7697.

* [Español (Spanish)](https://www.numotion.com/non-discrimination-notice/#NDN-spanish)  [繁體中文 (Chinese)](https://www.numotion.com/non-discrimination-notice/#ndn-chinese)  [Tiếng Việt (Vietnamese)](https://www.numotion.com/non-discrimination-notice/#NDN-vietnamese)  [한국어 (Korean)](https://www.numotion.com/non-discrimination-notice/#ndn-korean)  [Tagalog (Tagalog – Filipino)](https://www.numotion.com/non-discrimination-notice/#ndn-filipino)  [Русский (Russian)](https://www.numotion.com/non-discrimination-notice/#ndn-russian) فا[رسی (Farsi/Persian)](https://www.numotion.com/non-discrimination-notice/#ndn-farsi)
* العرب[ية (Arabic)](https://www.numotion.com/non-discrimination-notice/#ndn-arabic)  [Kreyòl Ayisyen (French Creole)](https://www.numotion.com/non-discrimination-notice/#ndn-french-creole)

© 2024 Numotion. All Rights Reserved.

Search Numotion.com:
